Guide to the Samuel R. Delany Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- May 2017 acquisition, 200.17; (249 boxes) + 1 record album storage
  - Materials deposited circa 1999, 1947-1999; 51.75; (52 boxes)
    These materials were previously held on deposit at the Howard Gotlieb Archival Research Center, Boston University. Samuel R. Delany deposited them circa 1999.
    - Manuscripts, 1952-1999
      - Novels, 1973-1998
        - Dhalgren, circa 1973 - 1996
          - Drafts of front matter - typescript with holograph corrections, circa 1973 - 1975 (Box 29)
            Also includes: typesetter's corrections lists; draft, bound photocopy of typexcript with photocopied and holograph corrections (circa 1975); draft, typescript with holograph corrections (circa 1974); final draft (?), photocopy of typescript with photocopied and holograph corrections (circa 1973).
          - Final draft (?), photocopy of typescript with photocopied and holograph corrections, circa 1973 - 1975 (Box 30)
            Also includes: drafts of chapters one and two, typescript with holograph corrections (circa 1973); draft of chapter four, typescript with holograph corrections (circa 1975); draft of chapter five, carbon typescript with holograph corrections; draft of chapter 6, typescript with holograph corrections (circa 1973); drafts of chapter seven; miscellaneous drafts, typescripts, carboncopy typescripts and photocopies of typescripts with holograph corrections (circa 1973); page proofs for Bantam edition, photocopy of typescript with photocopied corrections and holograph editorial notations (circa 1975).
          - Page proofs for Bantam edition, photocopy of typescript with photocopied corrections and holograph editorial notations, circa 1975 - 1996 (Box 31)
            Also includes: galley proofs for Wesleyan University Press edition, computerscript with holograph editorial notations (1996).
          - Galley proofs, with author's queries, holograph corrections, and editorial notations, 1974- (Box 32)
            Contains: Dhalgren galley proof, with author's queries, holograph corrections, and editorial notations.
          - Galley proofs, with editorial notations, circa 1974 (Box 33)
            Contains: Dhalgren galley proof, with editorial notations.
        - The Einstein Intersection, 1998- (Box 31)
          Contains: galley proofs, photocopy of typeset copy with holograph corrections and editorial notations, front matter. Also includes: correspondence with Mary Crittendon.
        - Equinox, undated (Box 31)
          Contains: draft, photocopy of typescript with holograph and photocopied corrections.
        - Hogg, circa 1973 - 1996 (Box 31)
          Contains: incomplete draft (circa 1973); miscellaneous drafts, typescripts or photocopies of typescripts with holograph corrections; draft, photocopy of typescript with holograph corrections (also includes: photocopies of published essays "The Scorpion Gordon" and "The Scorpion Gordon Revisited") (circa 1973); draft, photocopy of typescript with photocopied and original holograph corrections; final draft (?), computerscript with minor holograph corrections; galley proofs, computerscript with minor holograph corrections (1996).
        - The Mad Man, circa 1992 - 1996
          - Draft, computerscript with holograph corrections, undated, 1994-02 - 1994-06 (Box 34)
            Also includes: draft, computerscript with holograph corrections (1994 February 17); draft, photocopy of computerscript with Ron Drummond's corrections (1994 March 5); draft, photocopy of computerscript with holograph corrections (1994 March 5); draft, computerscript with holograph corrections (1994 April 20); draft, computerscript with holograph corrections (1994 May 26); draft, computerscript with holograph corrections (1994 June 17).
          - Draft, computerscript with holograph corrections, 1994-01-1996-01 (Box 35)
            Contains: draft, computerscript with holograph corrections (1994 June 17). Also includes: draft, computerscipt with holograph corrections (1994 June 23); draft, computerscript with holograph corrections (1994 November 15); draft, parts 4 and 5, photocopy of computerscript with holograph corrections (1994 February 5); photocopy of Masquerade edition with holograph corrections (1994 October 22); photocopy of Masquerade edition with holograph corrections (1995 February 4); photocopy of Masquerade edition with photocopied holograph corrections (1996 January); galley proofs with holograph and computerscript corrections (1994 January); photocopy of galley proofs with holograph corrections (1994 August 27, 1994 September 17); galley proofs (1994 January).
          - Miscellaneous notes, revisions, and publicity, undated, 1992-01 - 1992-05 (Box 36)
            Also includes: notecards (4x6), holograph (1992 January - May).
        - Neveryona #1, circa 1982 - 1993
          - Early draft, typescript with holograph corrections, undated (Box 36)
            Also includes: early draft #2, typescript with "Mog's" holograph notes and corrections; miscellaneous draft pages, typescript and computerscript with holograph corrections; precis with cover memo, computerscript with holograph corrections; page proofs, typescript with holograph corrections and editorial notation.
          - Galley proofs, typescript with holograph corrections and editorial notation, 1982-05-12-1993-08-09 (Box 37)
            Also includes: galley proofs, typescript with holograph corrections and editorial notation (1993 July 16); "Flight from Neveryon" galley proofs (1993 August 9).
          - Galley proofs with holograph corrections, 1982-06-03-1982-12-08 (Box 38)
            Also includes: galley proofs of front matter, including undated note from Lou Aronica to SRD (1982 December 8).
        - Flight from Neveryon, undated
          - Drafts of Part I, computerscript with holograph corrections, undated (Box 38)
            Also includes: drafts of Part II, computerscript with holograph corrections; drafts of Part III, computerscript with holograph corrections.
          - Drafts of Part III, computerscript with holograph corrections, undated (Box 39)
            Also includes: drafts of appendix A, computerscript with holograph corrections; miscellaneous draft pages, computerscript with holograph corrections; outline draft corrections, computerscript with holograph corrections; page proofs, computerscript with holograph corrections and editorial notation.
        - Return to Neveryon (or Bridge of Lost Desire), 1982-1993
          - Page proofs, computerscript and photographs with holograph corrections and editorial notes, 1985-11-1987 (Box 39)
            Also includes: drafts of Part I, computerscript with holograph corrections (1985 November).
          - Drafts of Part I, computerscript with holograph corrections, 1982-1987-02-27 (Box 40)
            Contains: drafts of Part I, computerscript with holograph corrections (1986 March - 1986 November). Also includes: drafts of Part II, computerscript with holograph corrections (1987 January 8 - 1987 February 27); drafts of "Appendix B: Closure and Openings", computerscript with holograph corrections; draft fragments, computerscript with holograph corrections; corrections, computerscript (1982 March, April, May 22).
          - Bridge of Lost Desire galley proofs, typescript with holograph corrections and editorial notations, 1987-05-11-1993-08-25 (Box 41)
            Also includes: Return to Neveryon galley proofs, typescript with holograph corrections and editorial notes (1993 August 25).
        - Tales of Neveryon, undated, circa 1988 - 1993 (Box 42)
          Contains: three galley proofs with holograph corrections and editorial notations.
        - Phallos!, 1995-1997
          - Drafts, computerscript, 1995 June 4 - 1997 Spring (Box 40)
            Contains: computerscript drafts.
          - Draft fragments, computerscript, undated (Box 43)
            Contains: computerscript draft fragments.
        - Shoat Rumblin, undated, 1997 August - 1998 December (Box 43)
          Contains: draft of Part I, computerscript with holograph corrections (undated); draft of Part I, computerscript, sent to Mia Wolff (1997 August); draft, computerscript with holograph corrections (1998 January 13); draft of chapters 27-44, computerscript with holograph corrections (1998 February 23); draft of Parts I and II, computerscript with holograph corrections (1998 May 7); draft of Part II, computerscript with holograph corrections (circa 1998 February 10); chapters 24-44 (1998 April 28); draft of Part I, computerscript with holograph corrections (1998 May 11); draft of chapters 25-coda, computerscript with holograph corrections (1998 February 21); draft of chapters 1-24, computerscript with holograph corrections (1998 May 22); draft of chapters 1-19, computerscript with holograph corrections (1998 May 23 or 1998 September 18); draft of chapters 26-coda, computerscript with holograph corrections (1998 May 24); draft of chapters 1-25, computerscript (1998 May 27); draft of chapters 1-12, computerscript with holograph corrections, discarded (1998 July 15); draft of chapters 1-25, computerscript (1998 December 2); draft of chapters 1-8, computerscript with holograph corrections (1998 December 3); draft of chapters 26-coda, computerscript (1998 December 4).
        - The Splendor and Misery of Bodies, of Cities, undated, 1986 Spring (Box 43)
          Contains: synopsis, computerscript with holograph corrections (undated); drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections (1986 Spring); miscellaneous draft pages.
        - Stars in My Pocket Like Grains of Sand, undated, 1984 July 18 - 1984 August 3
          - Early notes, typescript with corrections, undated (Box 43)
            Contains: early notes, typescript with corrections
          - Early notes, typescript with corrections, undated (Box 44)
            Also includes: early draft, photography of typescript with holograph corrections; third draft of prologue and chapters 1-13, typescript; draft fragments, typescript with holograph corrections.
          - Draft fragments, typescript with holograph corrections, undated, 1984 July 18 - 1984 August 3 (Box 45)
            Also includes: miscellaneous draft pages, typescript and photocopy with holograph corrections; drafts of front matter (dedication, table of contents, historical chart, and synopsis), typescript with holograph corrections; galley proofs, typescript with holograph corrections and editorial notes (1984 July 18); galley proofs, typescript with holograph corrections and editorial notes (1984 August 3).
        - They Fly at Ciron, undated, 1991 - 1995
          - Early draft, photocopy and computerscript with holograph corrections, undated, 1991 September 20 - 1993 June 9 (Box 45)
            Also includes: "late middle" drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections; draft of manuscript, photocopy and computerscript, including cover letter from SRD to Henry Morrison (1991 September 20); galley proofs, including Ron Drummond to SRD (undated, 1992 July 24 - 1993 June 9).
          - Galley proofs: 1995 Tor Edition, photocopy with editorial notation, 1991-1995 (Box 46)
            Also includes: reader's reports, computerscript (1991); miscellaneous publicity, notes, and corrections, mixed media.
        - Tides of Lust, undated (Box 46)
          Contains: two bound photocopies
        - Trouble on Triton, undated, 1974 - 1975
          - Page proofs, typescript with holograph corrections and editorial notes, undated, 1974 - 1975 (Box 46)
            Also includes: miscellaneous draft pages, typescript with holograph corrections; early draft of manuscript, typescript with holograph corrections; draft of manuscript, including letters from SRD to "Sirs" (1974 - 1975); galley proofs, New England Press edition, photocopy of proof with holograph corrections and editorial notes.
          - Galley proofs, Bantam edition, typescript with holograph corrections and editorial notes, undated, 1975 November 25 (Box 47)
            Contains: galley proofs, Bantam edition, typescript with holograph corrections and editorial notes.
        - Starboard Wine, undated (Box 47)
          Contains: proof, typescript with holograph corrections.
        - Empire, undated (Box 47)
          Contains: page proofs, typescript with holograph corrections.
      - Memoirs, 1972-09-1987
        - Heavenly Breakfast, 1972-09- (Box 46)
          Contains: draft of manuscript, computerscript with holograph corrections (1972 September); miscellaneous draft pages, typescript with holograph corrections.
        - Motion of Light in Water, undated, 1987
          - Galley proofs, undated (Box 46)
            Contains: galley proofs, Arbor House edition.
          - Galley proofs, undated (Box 48)
            Contains: galley proofs, Arbor House edition. Also includes: galley proofs, Grafton edition; page proofs, computerscript with holograph corrections and editorial notation; final draft, photocopy of computerscript with holograph corrections; final draft, Grafton edition, mixed computerscript and photocopy of typescript with holograph corrections; draft, computerscript with holograph corrections.
          - Early uncut draft, photocopy of computerscript, undated, 1987 (Box 49)
            Also includes: draft with David Hartwell's editorial suggestions, photocopy with holograph corrections (1987 September 8); corrections for Grafton edition, photocopy of first edition and holograph corrections; additions and corrections for the 1989 Plume edition, computerscript with holograph corrections (1987 July); draft fragments for Plume edition changes, computerscript with holograph corrections.
      - Essay and short story collections, 1974-1999-09-15
        - Atlantis: Model 1924, 1992 December 20 - circa 1994 September 29, 1994 October 31
          - Galley proofs, first edition, typescript with holograph corrections, 1992 December 20 - circa 1994 September 29, 1994 October 31 (Box 49)
            Contains: galley proofs, first edition, typescript with holograph corrections (1994 August 26 - circa 1994 September 29, 1994 October 31). Also includes: drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections (1992 December 20 - 1993 January 13).
          - Drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections, 1993 January 15 - 1993 October 26, undated (Box 50)
            Contains: drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - Atlantis: Three Tales, undated (Box 50)
          Contains: galley proofs, first edition, typeset; galley proofs, Wesleyan edition, typeset; manuscript and publisher's correspondence, computerscript and photograph.
        - American Shore, undated (Box 50)
          Contains: photocopy of book with holograph corrections.
        - Distant Stars, undated, circa 1980
          - Distant Stars, undated (Box 50)
            Contains: draft of introduction, photocopy of typescript with holograph corrections; incomplete galley and page proofs, photocopies with holograph corrections and editorial notes.
          - Distant Stars, circa 1980 (Box 57)
            Contains: galley proofs, typeset with holograph corrections.
        - Discourse on Desire, undated (Box 50)
          Contains: drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections and photocopy of computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - Driftglass/Starshards, circa 1991 - 1992 June 11 (Box 50)
          Contains: galley proofs, 1991 Grafton edition, typeset with holograph corrections; final draft, computerscript and photocopy with holograph corrections; two essay drafts, front and back matter, computerscript with editorial notes (also includes: Alison Walsh to SRD, 1992 June 11); drafts of preface to "Ruins", computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - Longer Views, undated (Box 50)
          Contains: galley proofs, typeset with holograph corrections; errata and index drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - Shorter Views, undated
          - Draft, photocopies of computerscript with holograph corrections, undated (Box 50)
            Contains: draft, photocopies of computerscript with holograph corrections.
          - Draft, photocopies of computerscript with holograph corrections, undated (Box 51)
            Contains: draft, photocopies of computerscript with holograph corrections; errata, computerscript/fax.
        - Silent Interviews, undated (Box 51)
          Contains: 3 drafts of Introduction, computerscript with holograph corrections; draft of "Semiology of Silence", computerscript and photocopy with holograph corrections; 3 drafts of "Toto, We're Back!", computerscript with holograph corrections; 2 drafts of "Refractions of Empire", computerscript with holograph corrections; 2 drafts of "Sword and Sorcery...", computerscript with holograph corrections; 4 drafts of "Some Real Mothers...", computerscript and photocopy with holograph corrections; 2 drafts of Diacritics Interview, photocopy and computerscript with holograph corrections; draft of Callaloo Interview, computerscript with holograph corrections; 2 drafts of Kenneth James Interview, computerscript with holograph corrections; draft of Susan Grossman Interview, computerscript with holograph corrections; draft of K. Leslie Steiner Interview, computerscript with holograph corrections; 3 drafts of Appendix, computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - Starboard Wine, undated (Box 51)
          Contains: photocopy of book with holograph corrections; incomplete draft, photocopy and typescript with holograph corrections; incomplete manuscript, computerscript with holograph corrections and editorial notes; miscellaneous draft pages, computerscript.
        - Straits of Messina, undated, 1974
          - Photocopy of book with holograph corrections and editorial notes, undated (Box 51)
            Also includes: draft of "Of Sex, Objects, Signs...", typescript with holograph corrections; drafts of Preface, "Early Delany", "Tales...", and "Return", computerscript with holograph corrections; drafts of Author's Preface, "Scorpion Garden Revisited", and authors' profiles, typescript with holograph corrections; "Printer's Copy" of "Ruins/Foundations", computerscript with holograph corrections; miscellaneous draft pages, computerscript with holograph corrections.
          - 4 drafts and draft fragments of "Ruins/Foundations", computerscript with holograph corrections, undated, 1974 (Box 52)
            Also includes: early draft of "Anti-Pornography of SRD", typescript with holograph corrections (1974).
        - Times Square Blue, undated, 1999 September 15 (Box 52)
          Contains: draft, computerscript; draft, computerscript with holograph corrections; galley proofs, typescript with holograph corrections (1999 September 15).
        - Wagner/Artaud, 1983 October - 1987 December, undated (Box 52)
          Contains: photocopy of book with holograph corrections; fragments of page drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections and editorial notes; late draft of manuscript, computerscript with holograph corrections (1983 October - 1987 October); incomplete draft of manuscript, computerscript with holograph corrections (1983 October - 1987 December); 3 drafts of manuscript, computerscript with holograph corrections (1983 October); miscellaneous draft pages, computerscript with holograph corrections.
      - Interviews, 1983-1996
        - Interview with Matthew Baldwin, 1995-10- (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Matthew Baldwin, computerscript.
        - Interview with Joseph Bear, 1985-05-1985-08 (Box 52)
          Contains: 4 drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - Interview with Camera Obscura, undated (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Camera Obscura, computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - Interview with Christopher Casper, Pat Califia, and Robert Morales; Meta interviews with McCaffery and Gregory, 1982 - 1983, 1983 August 25 (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Christopher Casper, Pat Califia, and Robert Morales, computerscript with holograph corrections (1982 - 1983); Meta interviews with McCaffery and Gregory, computerscript with holograph corrections (1983 August 25).
        - Interview with Mark Dery, 1993 January/April (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Mark Dery, computerscript.
        - Interview with Fractal, 1995 May 25, 1995 June 1 (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Fractal, computerscript. Includes: SRD to David Gardner, 1995 May 25; SRD to David Gardner, 1995 June 1.
        - Interview with Susan Grossman, 1988-04-26- (Box 52)
          Contains: 2 drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - Interview with Harold Jaffe, 1996-08-10- (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Harold Jaffe, photocopy of galleys with holograph corrections.
        - Interview with Stig W. Jorgensen and Niels Dalgaard, 1989-08-17- (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Stig W. Jorgensen and Niels Dalgaard, computerscript.
        - Interview with Darcy Lockman, 1993-05-05- (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Darcy Lockman, computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - Allen Markman (with BAI-FM), 1981-01-14- (Box 52)
          Contains: Allen Markman (with BAI-FM), computerscript.
        - Interview with Larry McCaffery and Sinda Gregory, 1983-08-25-1985-12-19 (Box 52)
          Contains: 3 complete drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections; draft fragments, computerscript with holograph corrections; miscellaneous draft pages, computerscript with holograph corrections; 3 drafts, computerscript with holograph corrections (also includes: SRD to McCaffery, 1985 December 19).
        - Interview with Octavia Butler and SRD interview with Robert Morales, 1997-11-1998-07-22 (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Octavia Butler and SRD interview with Robert Morales, computerscript. Includes: fax cover, SRD to Morales (1998 July 22).
        - Interview with Tavia Nyango, 1994-11-03 (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Tavia Nyango, computerscript.
        - Interview with Dennis O'Neal; photocopy of articles, undated (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Dennis O'Neal, computerscript with holograph corrections; photocopy of articles.
        - Interview with Lance Olsen, 1992-10-1998-08-21 (Box 52)
          Contains: 2 versions, computerscript (1992 October). Also includes: SRD to Lance Olsen (1998 August 21).
        - Interview with Paradoxa, 1995-05-30- (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Paradoxa, computerscript and photocopy.
        - Interview with Joan Schimarski, 1989- (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Joan Schimarski, computerscript. Includes: letter from Schimarksi to SRD with 3 enclosures (1989 May 1).
        - Interview with "SG", 1988-04-26- (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with "SG", computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - Interview with Tatayuki Tatsumi, 1987? (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Tatayuki Tatsumi, photocopy of galleys with holograph corrections.
        - Interview with unidentified person(s?), undated, 1986 April (Box 52)
          Contains: computerscript with holograph corrections; draft fragments, computerscript with holograph corrections; computerscript; computerscript with holograph corrections, computerscript (1986 April).
        - Interview with Ka Vang, 1985-10-17- (Box 52)
          Contains: Interview with Ka Vang, computerscript with holograph corrections (fax).
      - Articles, essays, and public addresses, 1952-1998
        - Afterward: 1994 (Box 52)
          Contains: Afterward: 1994, computerscript.
        - "Afterwards", 1990-04- (Box 52)
          Contains: "Afterwards", photocopy of computerscript with holograph corrections.
        - "The Albert", 1986- (Box 53)